Guide to the Julie Gilbert Papers ca. 1940-1998 MSS 38 MSS 038
© 2009 Fales Library and Special Collections
Julie Gilbert Papers
ca. 1940-1998
MSS 038
© 2009 Fales Library and Special Collections
14.0 Linear feet (10 boxes)
The Julie Gilbert Papers are the materials the writer used while researching her biography Opposite Attraction: The Lives of Erich Maria Remarque and Paulette Goddard.
Gilbert, Julie Goldsmith
Provenance
Julie Gilbert donated her papers in July 1998.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions. Appointments are necessary to consult archive and manuscript materials.
Biographical Note
Julie Gilbert was born on July 21, 1949 in New York. Her father, Henry Goldsmith was a publisher and her mother, Janet, was an actress. She attended Boston University and has worked as a professional actress, writer and teacher. She has written biographies, novels and plays including Umbrella Steps, which became a film, and Ferber: The Biography of Edna Ferber and Her Circle, which was nominated for the National Book Critics Circle Award. She received a Pulitzer Prize nomination for Opposite Attraction, the result of the research contained in this collection.
Scope and Content Note
The Julie Gilbert Papers are comprised of the original manuscript of Opposite Attraction and its various stages, production and publicity files, research files for the biography containing both personal and business correspondence of Remarque and Goddard, legal files, photo duplications, both hard copies and cassette tapes of individual interviews, printed material used for research, and computer disks. The Julie Gilbert Papers contain a comprehensive collection of Gilbert's research and production files for Opposite Attraction with photocopied material dating from ca. 1940. Julie Gilbert's original organization of the archive was preserved as much as possible.
SERIES DESCRIPTIONS
SERIES I: Written and Printed research materials
Includes clippings, notes, and published materials as well as translations and interview transcripts.
SERIES II: Media
Includes audiocassettes, mini-cassettes and floppy disks containing recorded interviews, notes and drafts of the biography.
Arrangement
Julie Gilbert’s original organization of the archive was preserved as much as possible.
The files are grouped into 2 series:
I: Written and Printed research materials
II: Media
Goddard, Alta; Goddard, Paulette, 1911-1990; Remarque, Elfriede; Remarque, Erich Maria, 1898-1970; Audiocassettes.; Biographies.; Clippings.; Correspondence.; Floppy disks.; Motion picture actors and actresses.; Notes.; Novelists, German - 20th century.; Photocopies.; Proofs (printed matter).; Transcripts
- Series I: Printed and written research materials
  - Source Citations, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Current Acknowledgements, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Part I Original edited typescript, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Part II Original edited typescript, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Part III Original edited typescript, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Part IV Original edited typescript, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Part V Original edited typescript, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Part VI Original edited typescript, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Part VII Original edited typescript, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Parts IX and X Original edited typescript, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Front Matter: Dedication/ Forward, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Part I First Pass, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Part II and III First Pass, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Part IV First Pass, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Part V First Pass, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Part VI First Pass, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Part VII First Pass, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Parts VIII and IX First Pass, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Epilogue First Pass, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Copyedited Typescript Page 1-150, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Copyedited Typescript Page 151-345, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Copyedited Typescript Page 347-478, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Copyedited Typescript Page 479-695, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Copyedited Typescript Page 696-476, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Photography Information Credits, Captions and 2nd Pass, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Second Pass, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Second Pass, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Second Pass, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Second Pass, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Opposite Attraction: Foul Matter, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Part I- Copy Edited by Shelly Wanger of Pantheon, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Part II- Copy Edited by Shelly Wanger of Pantheon, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Part III- Copy Edited by Shelly Wanger of Pantheon, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Part IV- Copy Edited by Shelly Wanger of Pantheon, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Part V- Copy Edited by Shelly Wanger of Pantheon, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Portion of edited original Edited by Shelly Wanger of Pantheon, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Typescript Page 1-180, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Typescript Page180-384, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Typescript Page 385-569, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Typescript Page 570-691, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Typescript Page 692-802, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Opposite Attraction Setting Manuscript Page 1-95, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Edited Typescript Page 96-234, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Edited Typescript Page 235-437, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Edited Typescript Page 438-632, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Edited typescript Page 633-763, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Edited typescript Page 764-861, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Rough Pages Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Rough Pages 121-282, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Rough Pages 283-450, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - German research materials and translations, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Research Materials, not from Fales, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Copies of Osnabrück material, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Research Materials, not from Fales, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Julie Gilbert on Paulette Goddard, undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Paramount Pretties excerpts from valuable movie biography regarding Paulette and very rare capsule family tree biography prepared by distant relatives of Paulette Goddard., undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Julie Gilbert's collected anecdotes of Paulette Goddard, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous preparations for publication of "Opposite Attraction" Ruth Marton changes Permission, source notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Inventory of Remarque's work compiled by Prior, Cashman, Sherman and Flynn, undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Transcripts of Elfriede Remarque's trial and beheading Translated by Henry Goldsmith (Julie Gilbert's father), undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Important early material (Remarque) Translations of early letters, Hans Rabe Osnabrück pamphlet, etc., undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Paulette: articles and letters to Alta, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Paulette's collection as the widow Remarque, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Sotheby's jewelry auction 1990: Paulette's jewelry, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Remarque: translation of an article Interview with Remarque, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - E.M. Remarque by Barker and Last (portions of), undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Remarque/Goddard miscellaneous research materials, undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Remarque's letters to Edith Doerry-Roseveare, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Transcript of Andy Warhol interview with Paulette, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Transcript of Andy Warhol interview with Paulette, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - To Ann Harris Re: Goddard collection at Tisch, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Alta's letters to Erich Paulette's letters to Alta, undated (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Time article, 1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Misc. notes and letters, undated (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Paulette Goddard's FBI file, undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - EMR to Ruth Albu/ Albu to EMR In German and translated, undated (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Paulette Goddard screenplay (assisted by EMR) Copies of Paulette's birth certificate, certificate of marriage to first husband and EMR and PG's marriage license, undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Copies of Remarque found objects, undated (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Master's Thesis, in German, on Remarque Written by Claudia Glunz, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Alain Bourgeois file-legal Re: Opposite Attraction, undated (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Opposite Attraction correspondence Re: publishing, foreign rights and publicity, undated (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Memorabilia from Opposite Attraction, undated (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Proposal for publication of Remarque's diaries English translation Unpublished in the USA as of 6/23/98, undated (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence with translator at Paul List Verlag, undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Remarque-Goddard book proposal Rejected by Julie Gilbert's agent, Joy Harris, because it is too short, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Opposite Attraction original cover Bride of Vengeance advertisement, undated (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Part One, undated (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Part Three, undated (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Part Five, undated (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Part Seven, undated (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Part Nine, undated (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Guide to material for Hoffman and Campe, undated (Box 4, Folder 93A)
  - Bibliography, Identification of source notes interviews, abbreviations, undated (Box 4, Folder 93B)
  - Part One with source notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Opposite Attraction German book review, undated (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - New Yorker, 9/11/1995 Opposite Attraction on "Recommended Reading" list, undated (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Publicity and Reviews, undated (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - EMR's letters to George Middendorf, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Letter of praise to poet named Henckell, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Letter to Ludwig Bäte, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Letter to Georg Middendorf, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Early writing- articles and poems, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Letter to a young woman in Horstemier Circle, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - H.G. Rabe's assessment, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Supposed political activities, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Letter to Henckell, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Test evaluation for teaching qualifications, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Letter to Mimi, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Early writings of EMR, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - The Dream Garrett, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Letter from EMR, teaching in Lohne re: Wulfren, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Deacon Brand episode, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Early writings of EMR, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Early writings of EMR, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Letter from Lolott (an actress), 1921 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Letter to Stephen Zweig, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Postcard to Karl Vogt, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Hanover Continental Tire Co., 1922 (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Postcard to Brigitte Neuner, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Echo-Continental Priemke cartoon, 1922-1923 (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - Letter to Karl Vogt, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Der Contibuben erster Streich Cartoon, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Re: All Quiet, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 123)
  - Letter to Georg Mittendorf, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - Interview with Axel Eggebrecht, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - Helen Murray, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - Letters to Brigitte Neuner, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 127)
  - Stories for Colliers, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - American Academy of Dramatic Art, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 129)
  - Stories for Colliers, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 130)
  - Article, "Telephoning Remarque", 1931 (Box 5, Folder 131)
  - Royalties for "All Quiet" and MGM contract "The Three Comrades" 1936, undated (Box 5, Folder 132)
  - Modern Times, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Clippings re: Paulette and Charlie Chaplin, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 134)
  - Paulette's fan club newsletter, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 135)
  - Gone with the Wind- Kanin spoof, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 136)
  - Excerpt from Douglas Fairbanks Jr. Autobiography, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 137)
  - Clippings and "The Road Back" agreement, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 138)
  - H.G. Wells paragraph re: divorce of Paulette and Chaplin, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 139)
  - Paulette Clippings, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - Veley-Lupe, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 141)
  - Misc. "Sweet Thing" telegrams, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - Maureen O'Sullivan letter, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 143)
  - Paulette Clippings 1942, undated (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - Contract between Charles Chaplin and Paulette Goddard, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 145)
  - Paulette Clippings, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - Elfriede Remarque's beheading, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 147)
  - Paulette Clippings, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 148)
  - Tax problem, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 149)
  - Paulette Clippings, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Remarque re: New client of Greenbaum, Wolff and Ernst, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - EMR letters to Jutta re: Colliers' money, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Paulette Clippings, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Remarque misc., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Info re: The Other Love- Enterprise deal, undated (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - Paulette's six-day tour of Germany, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - Arch of Triumph, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 157)
  - Arch of Triumph reviews, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 158)
  - Miscarriage letter, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 159)
  - Paulette clippings, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - Remarque and Ferber, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - Frances Cain letter, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Pilpel, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Paulette Clippings, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Letter from EMR to Ingrid Bergman, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Remarque on Germany, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Ernst, Morris, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - Passport- Remarque, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 168)
  - Paulette clippings, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 169)
  - G.I.'s letter, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - Re: Cosmopolitan negotiation for (Spark of Life?), 1949 (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - Re: Erich and Harriet, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - Paulette Clippings, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 173)
  - Publicity, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Frances Cain- sad letter, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - Love letter to Paulette that she mocks to E, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - Letters from Shepard Traube Re: bell, book and candle, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - Holiday correspondence W.H. Pilpel, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - Morris, William Agency re: bestseller program, funny letter, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 180)
  - Lantz, Robert letter re: Bestseller Theater, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - Spark of Life, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - Pilpel-Remarque, Mar 30, 1952-Apr 1, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - Pilpel- file memo, Mar-52 (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - Loos, Anita, Letter to Paulette around 1952 re: Gable, undated (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - Pilpel- radiogram Oct. 2, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Letters from "Toni", 1952 (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - Letter from Leo Koh(l?) re: Spark of Life, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - Paulette clippings, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - Letter from Paulette to Columbia Pictures (prod. of Paris model) re: her Huac position, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Paulette, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - To Alta from Ann- Paulette's former secretary, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Letter from Cole Porter to Paulette, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - A Time to Love and a Time to Die, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Paulette clippings, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Letters to H. Pilpel, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Letters to Paulette and Erich for Paulette to play Cleopatra, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Letters from Martin Gang re: Red Bait resurgence, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - Paulette to new sec/assist. Jeannette, ca.1955 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - Be Vigilant speech- Ten Days to Die, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - Paulette's letter to Alta, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 204)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - Berlin 1945 later full circle, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - Letters to H. Pilpel, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - EMR's divorce decree, undated (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - Paulette clippings, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - A Time to Love and a Time to Die, photo: Remarque and Pulver, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - Filming: A Time to Love, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - Paulette clippings, undated (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - Professor Peebley, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - Letters to H. Pilpel, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - Paulette in "Laura" Erich's telegram?, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - undated
  - Publicity re: Paulette and Erich's wedding, undated (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - Paulette clippings, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 219)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - Spark of Life/ All Quiet appraised by Abraham Lincoln Bookshop- Chicago, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - Spark of Life evaluation, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - Erich's letter to Alta, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - Erich to Paulette- living at 320 E. 57th, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - 1960 (Box 5, Folder 225)
  - Love letters from Erich to Paulette, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - Lindley, Denver letter to HP re: Time to Love, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 227)
  - Erich-Harriet re: Heaven Has No Favorites, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 228)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 229)
  - Remarque re: appraisal, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 230)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, undated (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - Erich to Harriet re: Heaven has no Favorites, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 232)
  - Paulette clippings, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - Re: Paulette's getting back to work, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 234)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 235)
  - Erich to Alta, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 236)
  - Alta's correspondence with Erich, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 237)
  - Remarque's letter to Paulette, approximately 1962-1967, undated (Box 5, Folder 238)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 239)
  - Goddard, Alta letters from Erich, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 240)
  - Pilpel, Harriet, letter to Erich re: Night in Lisbon, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 241)
  - Lantz, Robert letter to Harriet, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 242)
  - Paulette clippings, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 243)
  - Paulette's letter to Alta re: Remarque's heart spasm, undated (Box 5, Folder 244)
  - Age of Indifference- letter of support for her performance and reviews, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 245)
  - The Night in Lisbon- Times review, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 246)
  - Erich's letters to Paulette, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - Paulette's letter to Erich re: his small stroke, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - Erich's letter to Alta, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - Rod Steiger- Time of Indifference, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - Erich and Paulette clippings, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 252)
  - Erich's letters to Alta, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 253)
  - Pilpel, Harriet, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 254)
  - Paulette's letter to Erich, undated (Box 5, Folder 255)
  - Erich's letter to Paulette, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 256)
  - Paulette to Erich re: Age of Indifference dubbing, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 257)
  - Erich's letters to Alta, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 258)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 259)
  - Erich's letters to Paulette, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 260)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - Letter from Victoria Wolff, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - Erich's letters to Alta, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 263)
  - Erich's letters to Paulette, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 264)
  - Erich's letters to Paulette, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 265)
  - Erich's letter to Harriet re: rights, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 266)
  - Letters to Erich, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 267)
  - Letter from EMR to Mme. Buccerius and interesting article re: Paulette's life in Ascona, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 268)
  - Alta's letter to Erich, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 269)
  - Harriet correspondence re: rights- taking care of him till the bitter end, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 270)
  - Three Comrades- Indian thing, quite amusing, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 271)
  - Paulette's letter to Alta, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 272)
  - Erich's letters to Alta, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 273)
  - Paulette's letters to Erich, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 274)
  - Erich's letters to Paulette, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 275)
  - Paulette clippings, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 276)
  - Erich's letters to Alta (some of his last), 1970 (Box 5, Folder 277)
  - Legal files re: Paulette just after Erich's death, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 278)
  - Obituary of EMR, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 279)
  - Pilpel, Harriet re: estate, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 280)
  - Legal files re: Paulette, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 281)
  - Paulette clippings, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 282)
  - Crawford, Joan, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 283)
  - Shadows in Paradise- Times review, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 284)
  - Paulette's proposed Russian trip, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 285)
  - Estate matters re: Paulette, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 286)
  - Paulette's letters to Alta; Trip w/Anita Loos to Europe, undated (Box 5, Folder 287)
  - Roslyn Tara, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Re: Harriet and Paulette, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 289)
  - Paulette letter to unknown, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 290)
  - Letter from Paulette to Alta re: Michael Hall, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 291)
  - Paulette, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 292)
  - Sotheby's rejection, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 293)
  - Sotheby's re: Frida Kahlo tray, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 294)
  - Sotheby's contract for Kahlo tray, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 295)
  - Sotheby's re: Diego Rivera, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 296)
  - Obituaries, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 297)
  - Research, business, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 298)
  - Research, business, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - Research, business, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 300)
  - Research, business, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 301)
  - Research, business, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 302)
  - Research, business, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 303)
  - Research, business, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 304)
  - Research, business, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 305)
  - Research, business, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 306)
  - Research, business, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 307)
  - Research, business, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 308)
  - Research, business, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 309)
  - Research, business, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 310)
  - Research, business, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 311)
  - Research, business, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 312)
  - Research, business, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 313)
  - Research, business, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 314)
  - Research, business, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 315)
  - Research, business, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 316)
  - Research, business, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 317)
  - Research, business, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 318)
  - Research, business, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 319)
  - Research, business, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 320)
  - Research, business, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 321)
  - Research, business, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 322)
  - Research, business, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 323)
  - Research, business, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 324)
  - Research, business, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 325)
  - Research, business, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 326)
  - Research, business, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 327)
  - Research, business, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 328)
  - Research, business, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 329)
  - Research, business, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 330)
  - Research, business, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 331)
  - Pryor, Cashman, Sherman and Flynn, legal files, undated (Box 7, Folder 332)
  - Pryor, Cashman, Sherman and Flynn, legal files, undated (Box 7, Folder 333)
  - Photos from Fales collection, undated (Box 7, Folder 334)